

MOHAMED ANIS JENDOUBI

ROYAL PRIVATE AFFAIRS - KSA ASSISTANT FOOD & BEVERAGE MANAGER

OBJECTIVE

Food & Beverage professional who has built an extensive understanding of restaurants and hotel operations following 15 years of experience within top luxury brands and properties. Having worked in such establishments gave me the opportunity to develop a very objective and accurate understanding of what luxury customer service is about and how to train and develop a Team to work together to accomplish common targets.

SKILLS & ABILITIES

- Budget preparation and cost analysis
- Strong leadership and guest-focused team building skills
- > Event planning, marketing, and sales
- Excellent communication skills, including written and public speaking
- Independent leader with strong mentoring, supervisory, and motivational abilities
- Keen eye toward concept development and implementation
- Exceptional service-minded people skills
- Proficient in database, word processing, and POS software for all areas of hospitality marketing and management
- Adaptability in high-stress environments with ability to maintain composure and high level of professionalism
- Initiative and drive, problem solving and decision making
- Market demand and trend analysis

VITALS

Nationality: Tunisian Date of birth: 15/07/1978 Marital status : Married

Sex: Male

WhatsApp: +971503568 /+2 1654209103 E-mail: anis.jendoubi78@yahoo.com

EXPERIENCE

ROYAL PRIVATE AFFAIRS - KSA

ASSITANT F&B MANAGER DEC 2020 – FEB 2022

- Managing the operation of 3 palaces at long visits as well missions with short visits
- Daily walkthrough to the Family Club House, Golf Club House, 9 Guests Villas and 3 Principals Villas.
- Leading a team of 32 professional butlers, 25 mission's team, 7 baristas, 5 storekeepers, 3 vehicle drivers, 3 professional tailors, 12 laundry room attendants
- Delivering and coordinating personal preferences to the Royal Family members and their guests
- ❖ In charge of the main Royal Zone day to day operation
- Making sure all the necessary requirements for each VVIP event are ready ahead by planning together with all concerned executives
- ❖ In charge of the main Royal Zone day to day operation
- Making sure every new joiner receives his/her welcome pack, gets the RPA orientation, receives one week of trainings, then to be handed over to a buddy trainer
- Making sure there is a healthy work environment amongst colleagues and if necessary disciplinary action will be taken
- In charge of the manning schedule and colleagues allocation within the Royal Zone and off the Royal Zone
- ❖ In charge of the SOEs stores and logistics requirements
- Handled and executed certain operation projects such as selection of linen to three palaces, Ramadan operating supplies and decoration, employees' uniforms for three palaces...
- ❖ Making sure colleagues deliver the highest quality of Royal services

JACOB'S GARDEN HOTEL**** (DUBAI)

FOOD & BEVRAGE MANAGER (Pre-opening Team) AUG 2018 – JANUARY 2020

Jacob's Garden is a city business 4 stars hotel with 1 all day dining Indian buffet restaurant. It operates breakfast, lunch and dinner. It offers an international and Indian cuisine. The capacity is 320 seats indoor only coffee shop and 5 conference rooms leading a team of 47 colleagues

- Manage chefs, kitchen staff, and service team to provide stellar dining experiences to high-profile patrons.
- Achieving any objectives and targets given by the Exe -Management.
- Minimize and control expenses.
- To control manning and limit overtime.
- ❖ To hire, train, supervise and discipline all outlet staff.
- ❖ Maintaining stock level in line with finance directives.
- Coordinate with Sales & Marketing for food promotions.
- Oversee administrative tasks, including finance, training, equipment food ordering, maintenance and other needs as they arise.
- To develop and maintain an elegantly working environment, with superior staff, dedicated to an attentive, distinctive experience for all dining periods.
- Prepare annual and monthly budgets, cost analysis, employee performance reviews, and additional quarterly reports.
- Interact daily with hotel and dining guests to promote brand and accept feedback.

BARBEQUE NATION RESTAURANT (RAS AL KHAIMA)

BUSINESS MANAGER MAY 2017 – JULY 2018

- ❖ To strive to achieve desired financial budgets of the outlet.
- $\ \ \, \ \ \,$ To control breakage, manning and limit overtime.

ACHEIVEMENTS

- 7 years at Burj Al Arab Hotel and I got 2 promotions
- Star of the year2010 in F&B in Al Muntaha Restaurant at Burj Al Arab Hotel.
- 13 times Star of the month in AL Muntaha Restaurant at Burj Al Arab Hotel
- WSET Level 1 passed with distinction
- 100 % LQA score November 2013 in Al Muntaha Restaurants in Buri Al Arab Hotel.
- Training at Paul Bocuse Institute Lyon France: from 12 to 18 of May 2008 Wine and Cheese Trolley service
- Training at Adams Gasthof Restaurant in Dresden Germany:

Fine Dining a La Carte Restaurant and 4 private rooms for weddings and meetings from 1 /06/2006 till 31/8/2006

TRAININGS

- Hospitality Quality Standards to the Royal Palaces Tailored by Forbes
- PIC certificate with Merit valid from 11-03-2019 to 10-03-2024
- > Business Etiquette
- ➤ WSET level 1 Dubai
- English class level 3 at Burj AL Arab Hotel
- Hygiene training H.A.C.C.P at Burj AL Arab Hotel Dubai
- Coffee training at Burj AL Arab
- > First Step of Leadership at Burj AL Arab
- ➤ Lobster ink training Bar level 3
- Menu Engineering
- P&L Analysing
- Burj Al Arab Service Excellence Certificate from Jumeirah Hospitality
- Up Selling Technique (The Bob Brown Style)
- Complaint Handling Skills
- > Fire and Emergency Procedures

LANGUAGES

> Arabic: Mother tongue

French: FluentEnglish: FluentGerman: BasicItalian: Basic

REFERENCES

References are furnished promptly upon request with supporting documents.

- Implemented creative concept in concert with executive chef and partners.
- Recognized by partners for commitment to quality in preparation, presentation, training, and service.
- Ensure all guests are attended during dining.
- To control reservations and seating of the outlet.
- To ensure the correct and consistent service techniques for various events will be demonstrated by all colleagues.
- To be able to anticipate, in advance, all materials and supplies and assure their availability.
- Demonstrated budgetary needs and overhead expenditures to board of director through meetings and reports.

BURJ AL ARAB HOTEL ***** (DUBAI)**

ASST RESTAURANT MANAGER – AL IWAN (ARABIC CUISINE)

NOV 2015 - APRIL 2017

Al Iwan is an authentic Arabic fine dining restaurant. It is open for lunch and dinner, as well breakfast if the business requires. The capacity is 88 seats and it can accommodate over 200 guests in one meal period. Leading a team of 30 colleagues from different nationalities.

- To achieve departmental budget, goals and LQA scores.
- * Responsible for duty roster, vacation plan, all inventories
- Ensuring my team deliver good customer service and dealing with enquiries and complaints.
- Motivating staff and Conduct training for Team Leaders as well as general staff.
- Planning of new promotions to constantly provide quality choice of food in the restaurant.
- Plans for weekly life Music Show every Saturday
- Solicit open feedback from staff and guests by walking around.
- Ensure hygiene and cleanliness all around the restaurant and staff to maintain the standards

TEAM LEADER/ CHEF DE RANG – AL MAHARA FINE DINING (SEAFOOD FRENCH CUISINE) FEB 2014 – NOV 2015

TEAM LEADER/ CHEF DE RANG – AL MUNTAHA FINE DINING (EUROPEAN CUISINE)

JUL 2011 - FEB 2014

WAITER/ DEMI CHEF DE RANG – AL MUNTAHA FINE DINING (EUROPEAN CUISINE)

DEC 2009 - JUL 2011

- ❖ Always embrace companie Hallmarks
- Assist in hiring, training, supervising and discipline all outlet colleagues.
- Maintain a friendly yet unobtrusive manner with all guests.
- Possess a management ability that ensures a successful handling of the outlet
- To control reservations and seating of the outlet.
- Anticipate, in advance, all materials and supplies and assure their availability.
- Control usage of all food and beverage items and appropriate usage of equipment, tools and service equipment.
- Prepare colleague schedules, which allow for appropriate service while controlling labor costs and overtime.
- Communicate with other departments to ensure a supporting team of professionals.
- Communicate with the Outlet Manager, Chef, and Food and Beverage Director to discuss menus, marketing strategies and guest comments and concerns.
- * Ensures a safe working environment for all colleagues within the

outlet.

- To forecast covers and revenues and then schedules accordingly.
- To develop all colleagues for future advancement.
- To understand all food and beverage items offered, including ingredients, methods of preparation and proper service.
- To assist in completing and conducing performance evaluations for all colleagues.
- ❖ Leading a multicultural team of 26 colleagues

NAR & HAIL RESTAURANT (TAMANI HOTEL, DUBAI)

SENIOR CAPTAIN (ARABIC BUFFET)
OCT 2008 – NOV 2009

INTL BUFFET RESTAURANT (THALASSA HOTEL, TUNISIA)

HEAD WAITER (INTERNATIONAL BUFFET)
JUL 2008 – SEPT 2008

INTL BUFFET RESTAURANT (MARHABA HOTEL, TUNISIA)

HEAD WAITER (INTERNATIONAL BUFFET) JUN 2007 – JUN 2008

AFRICAN SUMMIT (PRESIDENT'S PALACE, LIBIYA)

HEAD WAITER
JUN 2007 – JUN 2008

EDUCATION

ISPT: (INSTITUT SUPERIUR PROFESSIONEL DE TOURISME SOUSSE AL KANTAOUI) TUNISIA

Hotel Management Bachelor Diploma (2004 - 2007)

ECOLE HOTELLIERE KARKOUANE HAMMAMET TUNISIA

Hotel Specialist Diploma in Service (2002 - 2004)